{"test_questions": [[{"question": "The function of the disengagement zone in an airlift fermenter is to", "opta": "prevent CO2 rich bubbles from entering the downcomer", "optb": "reduce the velocity of the bubbles", "optc": "reduce liquid loss as aerosols", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Stationary phase is described as", "opta": "no further increase in the cell population after a maximum value", "optb": "deceleration of growth and division rate after the growth rate reaches a maximum", "optc": "acceleration of growth and division rate after the growth rate reaches a maximum", "optd": "deceleration of growth and division rate after the growth rate reaches a minimum", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In the accelerated phase, cell starts to", "opta": "increase and the division rate increases to reach a maximum", "optb": "decrease and the division rate increases to reach a maximum", "optc": "increase and the division rate decreases to reach a maximum", "optd": "increase and the division rate increases to reach a minimum", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The monod model predicts that the specific growth rate", "opta": "will increase with the concentration of the growth limiting substrate until it reaches a maximum value", "optb": "will decrease with the concentration of the growth limiting substrate", "optc": "will increase with the concentration of the growth limiting substrate", "optd": "does not depend on growth limiting substrate", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A mixed fermentation is one, which produces", "opta": "both alcohol and carbon dioxide", "optb": "both acid and carbon dioxide", "optc": "both acid and alcohol", "optd": "several different kinds of acid", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The function of a mechanical seal is to", "opta": "prevent contaminants entering the reactor", "optb": "prevent cells from leaving the reactor", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "prevent air to enter", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The phenomenon in which substrates are used in a sequential manner is known as", "opta": "trans-substrate genesis", "optb": "dialism", "optc": "diauxie", "optd": "multiplicity", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The dilution rate, D is defined as(where F = volumetric flow rate, VR = total volume of culture in the reactor and \u03bc specific growth rate)", "opta": "F/VR", "optb": "VR/F", "optc": "\u03bc/F", "optd": "F/\u03bc", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Diauxie is", "opta": "growth factors", "optb": "microbiological die off", "optc": "the simultaneous uptake of nutrients", "optd": "the stagewise uptake of nutrients", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An open system in which the growth rate is maintained by adding a nutrient (present in limiting quantities) at the same rate as that medium containing micro-organisms is removed is called", "opta": "manostat", "optb": "chemostat", "optc": "turbidostat", "optd": "culturostat", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In the death phase", "opta": "nutrients available for the cells are depleted and begin to die", "optb": "the number of viable cells will increase", "optc": "nutrients available for cells are replenished and start to multiply", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The maximum specific growth rate of an organism depends on", "opta": "medium composition", "optb": "temperature", "optc": "pH", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not correct for the Monod model and the Michaelis Menten Model?", "opta": "The Michaelis Menten Model was derived from a curve fitting exercise", "optb": "The Michaelis Menten model was derived from an analysis of the mechanism of microbial growth", "optc": "The Monod model was derived from an analysis of the mechanism of microbial growth", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Bubble column reactor has", "opta": "large height to diameter ratio", "optb": "small height to diameter ratio", "optc": "large diameter to height ratio", "optd": "small diameter to height ratio", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Why a T-flask used in small-scale cell culture is incubated in a horizontal position?", "opta": "To save space", "optb": "To increase the surface area of the liquid-air interface", "optc": "Both (a) and (b)", "optd": "To increase the rate of oxygen transfer into the liquid", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An open system in which the growth rate is maintained by the removal and addition of media at such a rate as to maintain a constant cell density is called a", "opta": "manostat", "optb": "chemostat", "optc": "turbidostat", "optd": "culturostat", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Wash out in steady state fermentation occurs when", "opta": "dilution rate is less than maximum specific growth rate", "optb": "dilution rate is higher than the maximum specific growth rate", "optc": "cell concentration reaches the maximum", "optd": "specific growth rate is maximum", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Fermentor should be filled with medium upto", "opta": "65-70%", "optb": "70-75%", "optc": "75-80%", "optd": "80-85%", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Bacterial growth curve is obtained by plotting", "opta": "number of cells versus time", "optb": "number fo spores versus time", "optc": "log of number of cells versus time", "optd": "log of number of cells survived versus time", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When intracellular enzymes of whole cells are to be used in a bio-conversion process, it is often necessary to____________the cells.", "opta": "permeabilize", "optb": "lyophilize", "optc": "heat-kill", "optd": "denature", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Heat transfer rates (per unit volume) will be lowest in", "opta": "Stirred tank bioreactor with biomass recycle", "optb": "Continuous air lift bioreactor", "optc": "Continuous packed bed reactor", "optd": "Continuous fluidized bed bioreactor", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The function(s) of the draft tube in an airlift bioreactor is", "opta": "to reduce bubble coalescence", "optb": "to improve circulation", "optc": "to even out shear conditions throughout the reactor", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The Monod Model relates", "opta": "substrate utilized with the biomass consumption", "optb": "specific growth rate to the substrate availability", "optc": "yield with the biomass utilization", "optd": "the biomass concentration with specific growth rate", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The height to diameter ratio (H/D) for the column fermenters is", "opta": "<3", "optb": ">3", "optc": "<1.5", "optd": ">1.5", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The high oxygen transfer efficiencies of airlift bioreactors is due to", "opta": "the large aspect ratio of the reactor, which leads to a high gas hold-up", "optb": "the large aspect ratio of the reactor, which leads to a high oxygen solubility at the base of the reactor", "optc": "the draft tube, which reduces bubble coalescence in the reactor", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The maximum specific growth rate (\u03bcm) of an organism in batch culture is equal to slope of a plot of", "opta": "In [biomass] against time for exponential phase data only", "optb": "In [biomass] against time", "optc": "biomass against time", "optd": "biomass against time for stationary phase data only", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The region of an airlift bioreactor in which the liquid travels in a downward direction is called the", "opta": "downcomer", "optb": "disengagement zone", "optc": "air riser", "optd": "flotsam", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Population doubling time, td can be expressed as (where \u03bc is the specific growth rate.)", "opta": "log2/\u03bc", "optb": "ln2/\u03bc", "optc": "\u03bc/ln2", "optd": "\u03bc/log2", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A higher Ks value of Monod's equation means", "opta": "greater affinities to substrate", "optb": "lower affinities to substrate", "optc": "unaffected with the substrate bonding", "optd": "lower dissociation constant value", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The increased air flow rate in bubble column fermenter can cause excessive foaming and high retention of air bubbles in the column which", "opta": "decreases the productivity of the fermenter", "optb": "increases the productivity of the fermenter", "optc": "modestly increases the productivity of the fermenter", "optd": "does not affect on the productivity", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is correct for the prediction of time requirement in a batch fermenter?", "opta": "Carrying out experiments", "optb": "Mathematical modelling of the fermentation process", "optc": "Both (a) and (b)", "optd": "It is impossible to predict the time required for fermentation", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In an airlift bioreactor, the spent gases released from the liquid are called", "opta": "downcomer", "optb": "disengagement zone", "optc": "air riser", "optd": "flotsam", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The contents in jet loop reactor are mixed through", "opta": "compressed air", "optb": "a mechanical agitator", "optc": "external pumping", "optd": "any of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The specific growth rate (\u03bc) is defined as", "opta": "the concentration of biomass in the reactor", "optb": "rate of increase of total biomass in a reactor", "optc": "the rate of individual cells division or increase in their biomass", "optd": "the rate of cell death", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The number of baffles in a standard stirred tank bioreactor is", "opta": "8", "optb": "6", "optc": "4", "optd": "2", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In the stationary phase", "opta": "growth is proportional to death", "optb": "growth rate is equal to death rate", "optc": "growth rate is lesser than death rate", "optd": "no co-relation exist between death rate and growth rate", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is an example of a mathematical model?", "opta": "Volume of cuboid = length x breadth x height", "optb": "The Monod Model", "optc": "The Michaelis Menten Equation", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Biomass concentrations during fermentation is", "opta": "diluting the samples to optical density less than 0.3", "optb": "monitored by controlling the changes in biomass concentrations", "optc": "considering that optical density is proportional to the surface area of the biomass in the sample", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Chemostats work on the principle of", "opta": "maintaining constant volume of culture medium", "optb": "maintaining continuous flow of nutrients", "optc": "maintaining uniform nutrients concentration", "optd": "operating at higher pressure", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "During the exponential phase the maximum specific growth rate equals specific growth rate as", "opta": "concentration of the growth limiting substrate is much less than the monod constant", "optb": "concentration of growth limiting substrate is much greater than the monod constant", "optc": "specific growth rate increases exponentially", "optd": "concentration of the growth limiting substrate is equal to the monod constant", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}